( singing in Japanese )
♪
♪ PROUD OF MYSELF ♪
( Eugeo gasps )
Bercouli: THERE. NOW I’M READY.
Bercouli: ALL RIGHT, KID,
BEFORE WE GET INTO IT,
THERE’S SOMETHING
I WANNA ASK YOU.
Eugeo: WHAT?
Bercouli: YOU DIDN’T, YOU KNOW,
KILL VICE COMMANDER FANATIO,
DID YOU?
Eugeo: SHE’S ALIVE.
SHE’S BEING HEALED AS WE SPEAK.
( Bercouli sighs )
THAT’S GOOD.
SINCE YOU SPARED HER LIFE,
I’LL RETURN THE FAVOR
AND SPARE YOURS.
( Eugeo gasps )
HOW DISRESPECTFUL.
( Bercouli chuckles )
WHY DO YOU THINK THAT?
Eugeo: IF YOU’RE THIS HIGH UP
IN THE CATHEDRAL,
YOU MUST BE THE COMMANDER
OF THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS.
Bercouli: YEAH, WHAT IF I AM?
Eugeo: WHAT ABOUT THE OTHERS?!
FANATIO ISN’T THE ONLY KNIGHT!
ELDRIE, THE FOUR
WHIRLING BLADES, ALICE...
WHAT ABOUT THEM?!
DON’T THEY MATTER?!
Bercouli: I SEE.
YOU’RE TAKING THAT ROAD.
HOW DO I PUT THIS?
ELDRIE IS ALICE’S APPRENTICE.
THE FOUR WHIRLING BLADES--
DAKIRA, JACE,
HOVEREN, AND GEERO--
THEY’RE FANATIO’S.
AND HER? WELL,
SHE HAPPENS TO BE MY APPRENTICE.
IT’S NOT THAT I
DON’T CARE ABOUT THE OTHERS.
IT’S JUST
I’M INVESTED IN FANATIO.
THAT’S WHY, IF YOU KILLED HER,
I’D BE OBLIGED TO AVENGE HER.
THAT’S ALL THERE IS TO IT.
( chuckles ) THOUGH,
NOW THAT I THINK ABOUT IT,
I GUESS LITTLE ALICE DOES
LOOK UP TO ME AS HER MENTOR.
SHE’S NOT THE SAME
AS SHE WAS SIX YEARS AGO,
WHEN SHE FIRST BECAME
AN APPRENTICE KNIGHT.
IF ME AND HER WENT AT IT NOW,
I DON’T KNOW
WHO’D COME OUT ON TOP.
( Eugeo gasps )
Bercouli: ANYWAY, SEEING AS HOW
ALICE IS AS STRONG AS ME,
YOU MUST HAVE
SNUCK PAST HER SOMEHOW,
BUT YOU WON’T BE
SO LUCKY WITH ME.
COME TO THINK OF IT,
SHOULDN’T THERE BE TWO OF YOU?
THE PRIME SENATOR
SAID YOU HAD A PARTNER.
I GUESS,
IF HE’S NOT HERE WITH YOU,
THAT MEANS HE’S OFF SOMEWHERE
KEEPING LITTLE ALICE BUSY.
Eugeo: YEAH, HE PROBABLY IS.
I’M READY.
LET’S GET THIS OVER WITH.
I’M CURIOUS TO SEE
WHO’LL AVENGE YOU.
( Bercouli chuckles )
NO ONE, KID.
I DON’T HAVE A MENTOR.
♪
Eugeo: NORKIA STYLE,
LIGHTNING SLASH.
OR IT’S SOMETHING LIKE IT.
WITH HIS SWORD LIKE THAT,
IT’LL TAKE HIM
AN EXTRA MOVE OR TWO
TO ACTIVATE THE TECHNIQUE,
BUT IF I USE
THE AINCRAD STYLE’S SONIC LEAP,
I CAN STRIKE HIM FIRST.
Bercouli: AH, NOW,
THAT’S AN INTERESTING STANCE.
I’VE NEVER SEEN IT BEFORE.
DO YOU USE COMBO ATTACKS?
Eugeo: MAYBE I DO.
MAYBE I DON’T.
WHY DO YOU CARE?
Bercouli: I DON’T. IT’S JUST
THAT THERE WAS A KNIGHT
FROM THE DARK TERRITORY
WHO LIKED TO USE ’EM, TOO.
I FOUGHT HIM
A COUPLE OF TIMES BEFORE.
I DIDN’T LIKE THE EXPERIENCE,
TO BE HONEST.
MY STYLE’S SIMPLE.
DOING ALL THEM FLASHY MOVES
IS WAY TOO COMPLICATED.
Eugeo: IS THAT SO? DO YOU
WANT ME TO FIGHT LIKE YOU, THEN,
USING ONLY CONVENTIONAL MOVES?
Bercouli: HELL, NO. YOU WANNA
USE COMBO ATTACKS, GO AHEAD.
I CAN HANDLE
ANYTHING YOU DISH OUT, KID.
I SHOULD WARN YOU, THOUGH,
I’M GONNA USE
MY BEST MOVE FIRST,
AND YOU AIN’T READY FOR IT.
( Eugeo gasps )
IF HIS SWORD’S
ALREADY IN PERFECT CONTROL,
THEN I’VE ONLY GOT ONE CHANCE.
AS HE ACTIVATES HIS MOVE,
I’LL ATTACK WITH SONIC LEAP.
Bercouli: TASTE THE BLADE
OF BERCOULI SYNTHESIS ONE.
EN GARDE.
Eugeo: BERCOULI?
♪
( chorus vocalizing )
( Bercouli grunts )
( ticking clock slows )
( Eugeo yelling )
( gasps ) THAT RIPPLE,
IT’S WHERE HE JUST SLASHED.
( groans )
( gasping )
Bercouli: OOF.
TALK ABOUT CUTTING IT CLOSE.
THE LAST THING I EXPECTED
WAS FOR YOU TO COME
RUSHING IN AT ME LIKE THAT.
SORRY, KID.
I DAMN NEAR KILLED YOU.
Eugeo: YEAH, I KNOW YOU DID,
BUT WITH WHAT?
Bercouli: THAT WAS MY BEST MOVE,
JUST LIKE I TOLD YOU.
WHEN I TOOK THAT SWING,
I WASN’T JUST SLICING AIR.
I WAS SLICING A MOMENT
IN THE FUTURE, SO TO SPEAK.
Eugeo: SLICING THE FUTURE?
Bercouli: THE FIRST TIME I SAW
A DARK KNIGHT USE A COMBO ATTACK
WAS JUST AFTER I BECAME
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT MYSELF.
THE SWORD TECHNIQUES I LEARNED
WERE ALL ABOUT PUTTING
AS MUCH STRENGTH AS I COULD
BEHIND A SINGLE STRIKE,
BUT SWORD TECHNIQUES
USING COMBINATION MOVES
FOCUS ON HOW TO HANDLE
YOUR ENEMY’S ATTACKS
AND LAND HITS.
IT’S PRETTY OBVIOUS WHICH
IS MORE PRACTICAL IN A FIGHT.
ANYWAY, I GOT BEAT UP REAL GOOD,
BUT I SURVIVED.
THEN I GOT TO THINKING
HOW I COULD LAND A HIT
AGAINST A COMBO USER.
I FOUND THE ANSWER
WITH THIS THING.
ORIGINALLY IT WAS PART OF
A DIVINE OBJECT CALLED A CLOCK.
IT USED TO HANG ON THE WALL
OF THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL.
IT WAS HERE WHEN THE WORLD
WAS FIRST CREATED,
OR SO I WAS TOLD.
IT HAD A WEIRD NAME.
THE PONTIFEX
CALLED IT "SYSTEM CLOCK"
OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
WHEN LITTLE ALICE
USES HER OSMANTHUS BLADE,
IT CUTS THROUGH
THE HORIZONTAL AXIS OF SPACE,
BUT MINE CUTS
THE VERTICAL AXIS OF TIME.
NOW IT’S GOT A NEW NAME,
THE TIME-SPLITTING SWORD.
Eugeo: WHEN HE SWUNG IT,
THE FORCE OF HIS STRIKE
STAYED IN PLACE.
THAT MEANS I DON’T HAVE
A CHANCE AGAINST HIM UP CLOSE.
I’LL HAVE TO USE
LONG-RANGE ATTACKS.
SYSTEM CALL. CONNECT ARMAMENT.
- SEARCH ARCHIVED MEMORY.
- Bercouli: LET ME GUESS.
YOU’RE SETTING YOURSELF UP TO
ATTACK FROM A DISTANCE, RIGHT?
EVERYONE WHO SEES
THAT MOVE DOES.
SAME GOES FOR ALL
THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
THAT CAME AFTER ME,
INCLUDING FANATIO AND ALICE.
ONCE THEY SAW THAT MOVE,
THEY PICKED
LONG-RANGE PERFECT CONTROL
TO TRY AND DEAL WITH IT.
I CAN’T BLAME ’EM.
TRYING TO BRING ME DOWN
GOT TO BE SORT OF
A CONTEST BETWEEN ’EM.
BUT I NEVER LOST.
I SPARRED WITH ALL OF ’EM,
AND HERE I AM,
STILL THEIR COMMANDER.
WELL, IF ONE OF ’EM
DOES TAKE MY JOB,
IT’LL PROBABLY BE ALICE.
I SURE AM LOOKIN’ FORWARD
TO THIS, THOUGH.
I’M CURIOUS TO SEE
WHAT KIND OF MOVES
HELPED YOU GET PAST
ALL THOSE KNIGHTS.
Eugeo: DON’T WORRY. YOU WILL.
( Bercouli chuckles )
COME AND GET IT, KID.
THIS TIME,
I WON’T GO EASY ON YOU.
Eugeo: ENHANCE ARMAMENT!
♪
( Bercouli grunts )
( Eugeo yells )
( Bercouli yells )
( ticking clock slows )
( gasps )
( Eugeo roars )
( Bercouli yelps )
( Eugeo grunts )
( ice shatters )
( Bercouli gasps )
CLEVER.
( Eugeo roars )
BLUE ROSE SWORD...
LEND ME YOUR POWER.
RELEASE RECOLLECTION!
Cardinal:
NOW PAY CLOSE ATTENTION.
THE PERFECT WEAPON CONTROL ART
HAS TWO STAGES,
ENHANCE AND RELEASE.
Kirito: ENHANCE?
- Eugeo: RELEASE?
- Cardinal: YES.
ENHANCING AWAKENS
PART OF YOUR WEAPON’S MEMORIES.
THE ACT CAUSES
A NEW ATTACK TO MANIFEST.
IN THE RELEASING STAGE,
YOU CAN AWAKEN
ALL OF YOUR WEAPON’S MEMORIES.
THEN YOU CAN UNLEASH
ITS MOST SAVAGE POWER.
Kirito: OH. I GET IT.
♪
THAT EXPLAINS ELDRIE’S WHIP.
IN ITS ENHANCED STAGE,
IT CAN GET LONGER THAN NORMAL
AND THEN SPLIT.
♪
Eugeo: THEN ITS RELEASE STAGE
WAS WHEN IT CHANGED
INTO A SNAKE.
Cardinal: YOU ARE CORRECT.
THAT SAID,
YOU TWO SHOULD AVOID USING
RELEASE FOR THE TIME BEING.
Eugeo: WH-WHY SHOULD WE?
Cardinal: BECAUSE YOU ARE
NOT YET READY TO.
YOU HAVE ONLY
JUST LEARNED OF THE ART.
UNTIL YOU MASTER IT,
YOU CANNOT CONTROL
THE POWER GENERATED
BY YOUR WEAPON’S MEMORIES,
ESPECIALLY THOSE
OF A DIVINE OBJECT LIKE YOURS.
IT CAN HARM YOU
AS MUCH AS YOUR ENEMY.
IF YOU’RE NOT CAREFUL,
IT WILL KILL YOU.
( ice crackling )
( Eugeo chuckles )
( Bercouli gasps, chuckles )
I NEVER SAW A SWORDSMAN TOSS
HIS BLADE DURING A FIGHT BEFORE.
DID YOU COME UP
WITH THAT TRICK YOURSELF?
Eugeo: UH-UH.
MY PARTNER TAUGHT ME THAT ONE.
THE BATTLEFIELD
HAS LOTS OF OPPORTUNITIES.
ANYTHING CAN BE
A WEAPON OR A TRAP.
( Bercouli chuckles )
MAKE THE BEST
OF WHAT YOU GOT. SMART.
WELL, YOU MIGHT HAVE GOTTEN
THE UPPER HAND THIS ROUND,
BUT THERE’S NO WAY IN HELL
YOU’RE GONNA BEAT ME!
♪
( growling )
( roars )
- ( Eugeo gasps )
- ( Bercouli chuckles )
Eugeo: THE BLUE ROSE SWORD
HAS TWO DORMANT MEMORIES,
ETERNAL ICE AND ROSE.
WHEN I ACTIVATE ETERNAL ICE,
IT FREEZES EVERYTHING.
NOW I’LL SHOW YOU
WHAT ROSE CAN DO.
BLUE ROSE, BLOOM!
( Bercouli gasps )
WHAT’D YOU DO?!
Eugeo: THE ROSES BLOOM
BY ABSORBING THE LIFE
OF THOSE TRAPPED IN THE ICE.
Bercouli: DAMN IT.
YOU LITTLE PUNK.
SO WAS THIS YOUR PLAN ALL ALONG,
KILLING THE BOTH OF US?!
Eugeo: NOT US. JUST YOU.
YOU HAVE AN ADVANTAGE OVER ME
IN EVERY WAY, EXCEPT ONE.
IT’S YOUR TOTAL AMOUNT
OF LIFE LEFT.
BASED ON YOUR APPEARANCE,
YOU BECAME AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
IN YOUR FORTIES,
SO YOUR LIFE VALUE
IS LOWER THAN MINE.
I’M YOUNGER, AND MY LIFE VALUE
IS NEAR ITS PEAK.
EVEN THOUGH YOU LANDED A HIT,
THE LIFE I HAVE LEFT
IS STILL HIGHER THAN YOURS.
THAT’S WHAT I HOPED, ANYWAY.
Bercouli: KID, YOU DON’T KNOW
WHAT YOU’RE TALKING ABOUT.
YOU JUST SAID I "BECAME"
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT.
A KNIGHT’S ALL I’VE EVER BEEN.
I DIDN’T HAVE A LIFE
BEFORE I WAS SUMMONED.
Eugeo: AND THAT’S THE PART OF
YOU PEOPLE I FIND SO DESPICABLE!
YOU’VE FORGOTTEN
WHO YOU USED TO BE.
YOU’RE LOYAL TO THE AXIOM CHURCH
WITHOUT KNOWING
WHAT IT REALLY IS.
YOU ACT LIKE YOU’RE
CHAMPIONS OF JUSTICE,
BUT YOU UPHOLD CORRUPTION!
YOU THINK YOU’RE HERE
BECAUSE THE PONTIFEX
SUMMONED YOU FROM HEAVEN,
BUT THAT’S A LIE!
YOU HAD A MOTHER.
SHE’S THE ONE
WHO GAVE YOU THE NAME BERCOULI.
YOU’RE HUMAN, JUST LIKE ME!
( gasps )
BERCOULI. IN MY VILLAGE,
THEY TELL STORIES
ABOUT HOW MUCH
OF A HERO YOU WERE.
( Bercouli gasps )
WHAT STORIES?
Eugeo: THINK BACK.
I’M SURE YOU’VE
SEEN THIS SWORD BEFORE.
Bercouli:
YEAH, I HAVE, SOMEWHERE.
RIGHT. YEARS AGO...
IT WAS IN THE NEST
OF THE WHITE DRAGON.
I SAW IT THERE
AFTER I KILLED IT.
Eugeo: YOU KILLED THE DRAGON?
I SAW ITS BONES...
AND NOW--NOW YOU SAY
THE ONE WHO KILLED IT WAS YOU?
A DRAGON
THAT PROTECTED THE HUMAN REALM,
THE ONE FROM YOUR OWN LEGEND.
DON’T YOU REMEMBER
ANYTHING ABOUT YOUR PAST,
ABOUT WHO YOU WERE?
IN RULID, THE VILLAGE YOU
FOUNDED AND WHERE I WAS BORN,
EVERYONE KNEW ABOUT YOU.
YOUNG OR OLD,
WE LOOKED UP TO YOU AS A HERO.
BUT THE PONTIFEX
SEALED AWAY YOUR MEMORIES.
SHE TURNED YOU
INTO THE FIRST INTEGRITY KNIGHT.
THEN CAME THE OTHERS,
EVERYONE FROM FANATIO TO ELDRIE,
EVEN ALICE,
ALL OF YOU.
BEFORE YOU BECAME
INTEGRITY KNIGHTS,
YOU HAD LIVES.
YOU WERE HUMAN.
Bercouli:
SEALED AWAY MY MEMORIES?
I CAN’T JUST BELIEVE
A WILD STORY LIKE THAT.
BUT ALL THAT STUFF I WAS TOLD
ABOUT ME BEING SUMMONED
FROM HEAVEN,
I HAD MY DOUBTS FOR A WHILE NOW.
( Eugeo shudders )
- ( bouncing )
- ( laughing )
♪
Man: WELL, WELL!
NOW, WHAT DO WE HAVE HERE?
( chuckles )
( laughing )
THIS WON’T DO. NO, NO, NO.
THIS WON’T DO AT ALL,
MY DEAR COMMANDER.
SURELY, GOOD SIR, YOU DON’T PLAN
TO DIE ON US LIKE THIS?
THAT WOULD BE TREASON
AGAINST HER EMINENCE,
THE LOVELY PONTIFEX.
IF SHE WERE AWAKE
TO SEE YOU IN THIS STATE,
SHE WOULD BE LIVID.
Bercouli:
PRIME SENATOR CHUDELKIN,
THIS IS A FIGHT
BETWEEN SWORDSMEN.
A PIG LIKE YOU
HAS NO BUSINESS HERE.
Chudelkin: HA HA HA!
AFTER GOING SO EASY
ON THIS HERETIC,
YOU HAVE NO BUSINESS
CORRECTING ME.
DEAR COMMANDER, PRAY TELL,
WHY DID YOU NOT USE
YOUR SWORD’S FULL POWER?
IF YOU HAD, YOU COULD HAVE
SLAUGHTERED THIS LOATHSOME BRAT
BEFORE HE OPENED
HIS SLANDEROUS LITTLE MOUTH.
BUT YOU DID NOT, AND, THEREFORE,
COMMITTED TREASON
AGAINST THE GLORIOUS PONTIFEX.
- Bercouli: SHUT YOUR MOUTH.
- ( Chudelkin gasps )
Bercouli: I FOUGHT
WITH EVERYTHING I HAD.
BUT YOU LIED TO ME.
YOU LIED TO ALL OF US.
THIS KID AIN’T NO ASSASSIN
FROM THE DARK TERRITORY.
AND COMPARED TO AN UGLY
PIECE OF SHIT LIKE YOU--
Chudelkin: SILENCE!
BE SILENT, OR I’LL
RIP OFF YOUR HEAD!
FOR YOUR INFORMATION, MY DEAR,
WE WOULDN’T HAVE THIS PROBLEM
IF YOU DAMNED KNIGHTS
WEREN’T SO DAMNED USELESS.
HONESTLY,
WHEN HER EMINENCE AWAKES,
YOU KNIGHTS WILL BE
THOROUGHLY PUNISHED.
AT THE VERY LEAST, YOU AND
YOUR PRECIOUS VICE COMMANDER
SHALL BE REPROCESSED.
Bercouli: "RE-" WHAT?
YOU’RE TALKIN’ OUT
YOUR ASS AGAIN.
( Chudelkin chuckles )
SYSTEM CALL! DEEP FREEZE!
INTEGRATOR UNIT I.D.
ZERO-ZERO-ONE!
( Bercouli gasps )
( Eugeo gasping )
( Chudelkin laughs )
WE DON’T NEED
OLD FARTS LIKE NUMBER ONE
STINKING UP THE PLACE ANYMORE.
NOW WE HAVE A MUCH YOUNGER,
- MORE USEFUL PAWN...
- Eugeo: KIRITO.
Chudelkin: AT OUR DISPOSAL.
Eugeo: ALICE.
Kirito: EUGEO.
Alice: IS SOMETHING THE MATTER?
Kirito: HUH? OH, NO. NOTHING.
AS SOON AS THE MOON COMES OUT,
I THINK WE CAN START
CLIMBING UP THE WALL AGAIN.
LONG AS I CAN MAKE SPIKES,
IT SHOULD GO PRETTY EASY
FROM HERE ON.
THERE’S NO MINIONS ABOVE US,
AND THE OTHERS HERE
AIN’T WAKING UP.
FOR NOW. BESIDES THE LACK
OF SACRED POWER,
THE ONLY OTHER BIG PROBLEM
IS FOOD.
I DON’T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I’M STARVING.
IF I THINK ABOUT
HOW MUCH FURTHER WE GOTTA GO,
MY HEAD STARTS SPINNING.
Alice: COULD YOU BE
ANY MORE OF A DISAPPOINTMENT?
Kirito: WHAT?!
Alice: WHETHER WE MISS
A MEAL OR TWO
IS THE LEAST OF OUR WORRIES,
UNLESS YOU ARE A CHILD.
Kirito: YEAH, WELL,
TECHNICALLY, I STILL SORT OF AM.
I MIGHT NOT ACT
LIKE IT ALL THE TIME,
BUT I’M NOT EVEN
OUT OF MY TEENS YET.
I DON’T EAT, MY LIFE GOES DOWN,
A PROBLEM
YOU BADASS KNIGHTS DON’T HAVE.
Alice: SUCH LANGUAGE!
EVEN INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
GET HUNGRY.
WE MUST EAT,
OR WE LOSE LIFE LIKE YOU.
- ( stomach grumbles )
- ( both gasp )
( Kirito snickers )
WHOA! HOLD ON!
SORRY! I WAS KIDDING!
OF COURSE YOU GET HUNGRY.
YOU’RE AS ALIVE AS ANYONE ELSE.
SPEAKIN’ OF FOOD,
WHERE ARE CARDINAL’S SNACKS?
Alice: HMM?
Kirito: AW, YEAH.
I KNEW I SNAGGED SOME MORE.
LOOKIT! IT’S DINNERTIME!
♪
Alice: WHY IN THE WORLD
WOULD YOU STORE YOUR FOOD
IN SUCH A WAY?
Kirito: I DON’T. I JUST TAPPED
MY POCKET, AND THERE THEY WERE.
TRY IT SOMETIME.
BUT FIRST I GOTTA
GET THESE READY TO EAT.
( chuckles )
( Alice groans )
Kirito: SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE THERMAL ELEMENT.
BURST ELE--
Alice: NO, YOU FOOL!
Kirito: WHAT?
Alice: IF YOU USE THAT ART,
YOU WILL BURN THEM!
Kirito: SORRY.
( gasps )
Alice: GENERATE THERMAL ELEMENT,
AQUEOUS ELEMENT,
AERIAL ELEMENT.
VORTEX SHAPE. BURST.
( steam hissing )
Kirito: WHOA!
HURRY! GIMME ONE!
( Alice chuckles )
Kirito: WAIT! NO, NO, NO!
Alice: I AM JOKING.
( Kirito chuckles )
( blows )
MMM.
THAT HIT THE SPOT.
THANKS FOR SHOWING ME THAT.
I DIDN’T KNOW
YOU COULD STEAM FOOD
USING ELEMENTS
INSTEAD OF A PAN.
DID YOU TEACH
YOUR LITTLE SIS HOW TO COOK?
’CAUSE SELKA’S
REALLY GOOD AT IT.
( gasps )
Alice: WHAT DID
YOU SAY JUST NOW?
( Kirito gasps )
THAT YOU HAVE A LITTLE SISTER.
HER NAME’S SELKA.
Alice: SISTER?
♪
( gasps )
Kirito: I CAN
TELL YOU ABOUT HER.
I CAN TELL YOU EVERYTHING
I KNOW ABOUT THIS PLACE.
I DON’T KNOW
IF YOU’LL BELIEVE ME,
BUT IT’S WORTH A SHOT.
( Alice sighs )
GO ON, THEN.
HOWEVER...
IF I DETECT EVEN
A TRACE OF DECEIT IN YOUR WORDS,
I SHALL END YOUR LIFE.
( Kirito gasps )
Singer: ♪ OH, EVERYTHING
TURNS TO ASH, TO ASH ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ AND EVERYTHING
TURNS TO DUST, TO DUST ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ FORGET-ME-NOT ♪